Namaste friends, for most of us, a
two-wheeler bike
is a must-have.
Everyone takes care of the maintenance of this bike from time
to time, that is, servicing, etc. If
we do not
maintain it from time to time, we neglect the most
important thing, the insurance of the bike.
So many people do not have insurance for their bikes. They do not take out
insurance renewal. For
those who buy a new bike, one
plus four years means one year of full
insurance, four years of third-party
insurance, which is the same with the bike. But
after one year, you should take out bike insurance renewal from the second year. Only if you take out renewal, in the
future, if your bike is accidentally
stolen by someone, or if it is
accidentally damaged in an accident somewhere, or if it is
accidentally damaged in a fire accident, the bike
burns.  However, if there are any such things, the
full amount of coverage related to your bike will
be refunded to you. With that amount,
you can buy a new bike again. You can purchase a
new bike.
Many people do not know this and neglect insurance. They make
many unnecessary expenses but do not
concentrate on bike insurance. So,
after watching this video, if any of you want to get
bike insurance involved,
watch this video and
renew your bike insurance yourself.
I will
explain the process step by step to you. You
can also compare the prices outside.
Now, in the process that I am telling you,
you will get the insurance renewed at a lower price.
So, enter your bike
details and
renew your bike insurance in five minutes. So, let's
start the process without delay. If you have
not done so yet, subscribe to our channel.  Subscribe and
put the bell next to it. Give a like to the video. If you like it, it will
be supportive for me. So to renew your bike insurance, the
official link is
given in the description and in the comment box. Just click on that link.
You will come to the Ekko Insurance page that is shown on the screen.
Friends, just enter your bike number here and
click on View Prices.
Here, it will
ask for the current policy status of your bike. That is, if the insurance of your bike has expired and is
more than 90 days old,
select More than 90 days. If it has
expired recently and is not 90 days old,
select Last 90 days.
Some people take
precautions before their bike insurance expires.
So, for
such people,
select Not Expired. Then, all your bike
details will also come here. Here, your
bike model and year.  If the registration year is
correct, then it is okay. If not, then
click on Edit and select your bike model here.
From here, select the
year you bought your bike or the registration year and
click on View Plans. Here you will
get insurance policies. Here there are
one-year insurance policies, two-
year policies, three-year policies.
Select how many years you want to do it. Here it shows me 1400 1300, so don't get
stressed that it will show you the same amount.
Depending on the CC of your bike, the price will be given to you according to the model of your bike. The
CC of the bike I gave is higher, so the higher amount will be
shown. Then below, the
insurance policy types will come. In
total, there are three types of policies in insurance policies.
First, the
comprehensive plan for vehicles.
What is a comprehensive plan? This
means that if your bike ever gets into an accident in the future and gets damaged, if your bike gets damaged by fire, if
your bike gets damaged, if your bike gets damaged by fire,
Theft means that if someone
steals your bike, the insurance company will
provide you with a claim, which means that
you will have to buy a new bike
or get it repaired,
and so on. This
also includes the third party. The third
party means that when you have an accident with your bike, the other person dies or gets injured, or there is no
other person, or there is a property, if
that property is damaged, the
insurance company will
also
provide coverage to the third party. This is a comprehensive
plan. After the third party plan, the
third party plan
does not provide any insurance for your bike if there is any damage to it, a fire, or theft. The company
provides only to the third party. The third party means that I have already said that the third party  If you
damage a person or another person's property, then
this company provides insurance only for them.
So who will
take the third party? Mostly, it doesn't matter if our bike gets damaged, but if our bike gets stolen, it doesn't matter if we have insurance at the police check. They say that it is enough if we have insurance at the police check. They take the third party and
apart from this third party, there is another one called own
damage.
What is own damage? For example, if you
buy a new bike, when you buy a new bike,
they
give you a five-year insurance plan. If not,
five years is
not full insurance. First, only the first year will
you have full insurance, i.e.
comprehensive, for your bike, for the other party as well, for the
third party.
Then from the second year, only the third party will be there. From the second year, only the third party will be there. From the second year, only the third party will be there. From the second year, only the third party will be there.
From the second year,
only the third party will be there, i.e. for the police check
and for the other party, whenever any damage
occurs.  If you make an insurance claim,
you have to pay a penalty to the other party for the
damage. The
insurance company does not
give you any insurance except for the amount that was given to them. So, if
anything happens to your bike during these four years,
how do you get coverage? That is, you should
take an own damage plan. So,
what comes in an own damage plan? That is, if
your bike gets
damaged in an accident, fire, theft, etc.,
this insurance company will
bear the cost of damage to your bike. So, in these three plans,
only the own damage plan is available. Those who have recently bought a new bike,
one year has passed and there
is still a third party for four years, take the own damage plan. The rest do not take it.
And if their bike is
more than five years old, they should
purchase a comprehensive
plan, that is, full insurance or
third party, whichever you can afford.
Third  Full
insurance is an extra ₹100 or so over the party insurance.
I would suggest you a
comprehensive insurance.
So, if you
select comprehensive and click on continue,
I will show you some add-ons later.
In the add-ons, personal
accident cover means that you
have insured only your bike,
not the owner on the bike, so the owner should
also
get personal accident coverage. If you think that he is injured or dies,
you can
take it by paying an extra ₹350 and adding it. This is compulsory in any insurance company. You
can take it if you like, otherwise, no. So if you
think that you need it, if you click on the add, the 350
amount will be extra. If not, then you will
also get coverage for the bike owner
and apart from that, if you
scroll down further, you will get helmet
protection, engine protection,
consumables, repair.  When it happens, there
are nuts, bolts, etc.
They will also show you all of them. If you need them,
take them. If not, then
click on Continue. Here, your full name will
automatically be displayed as it is in your bike RC card. If it is
correct, then
it is okay. If not, edit it and
correct it. Then enter your email ID. Then
enter your mobile number. Then
enter your PIN code. You do not need to enter anything under GST number.
Leave it blank and click on Continue.
Then check your bike details. It says
your bike number, model, or
registration year. But
check all these once. If they are correct
or not, scroll down and see if
your name, email ID, mobile number, and owner details are
correct. If you
scroll down,
you will see that the premium here is ₹990 and 18%
GST is added. Now you
know that whatever you purchase in India,
18% GST will be charged. So
after GST is added, you will
Click on Pay Now to make the payment.
Now you
have multiple ways to pay this amount. You can pay from Phone
Pay, Google Pay, Paytm on your mobile.
Otherwise, you can pay
using your debit card, credit card, or
net banking.
What is the easiest method?
Everyone is using Phone Pay these
days. So just select Pay Now on Phone Pay.
Click on Pay Now. So, if you get a Phone Pay notification on your mobile from above and
click on Pay Now, the
amount will
be shown to you. If you click on Send and
select MP, then the amount has been
paid successfully. If you
get a return from Phone Pay, you will
come to the insurance page again. Here you will see the
insurance start date, end date, and
expiration date. All these
details are also shown here. I am giving you this
as a reference.  I
am showing you what I did before, so
confirm the dates like this, then
download the document and
put it on your mobile. Just
click on download, if
you have a PDF document, if you
click on PDF, the
PDF file will be downloaded to your mobile. If you
click on WhatsApp,
they will also
send your insurance document to your WhatsApp,
it will remain forever. If you click on email, they will
mail you the document. The
insurance document will remain forever in the mail. In
this way, you can
choose three options. You can get the
insurance
document from wherever you need it in the future.
So in this way, you can
renew the insurance for your bike at a low price and
after the insurance renewal, download the
insurance document that I will show you and
put it on your WhatsApp or email. Wherever you have
any need related to insurance, where there is a police check,
you can do that.  It is
enough to show the document and if in the
future your bike is stolen
or in an accident or in a
fire accident, there
is an Eco Insurance Claim Helpline number shown here
on the screen.
Call that number and tell us about your problem.
Tell us while we are live there. So they will
verify the problem in the video call. After
verifying,
they will provide you with all the details related to the insurance claim and will
also do the entire claim process.
So this is a complete video. If
you have any doubts in this, comment below.
For more such videos,
subscribe to our channel and
press the bell icon next to it. See you in another good video.
Thank you for watching. See you in the
next video. Jai Hind.